Guide to the Graphics collection, 1740-1995 MS2379
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Graphics collection
Circa 1740 - Circa 1995
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2379
18 Linear Feet
This is an artificial collection composed of images acquired by Special Collections Research Center at various times. The collection was created in 2018 from original MARC records. The collection contains photographs, glass negatives, lithographs, engravings, prints, drawings and scrapbooks related primarily to the history of Washington DC and the Metropolitan area. More broadly the subject is American History. The images date from approximately 1740-1995.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Graphics, Oversize graphics, and Graphic collections
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Images acquired over time from many sources.
Biographical / Historical
This is an artificial collection composed of images acquired by Special Collections Research Center at various times. The collection was created in 2018 from original MARC records.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs, stereocards, glass negatives, lithographs, engravings, prints, drawings and scrapbooks related primarily to the history of Washington DC and the Metropolitan area. More broadly the subject is American History. The images date from approximately 1740-1995.
- Graphics, 1740-1995; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged in original order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains graphics, stereocards, and other image formats related primarily to the history of Washington DC and more broadly American history.
  - J. Barlow from the original painting by Chappel in the possession of the publishers., Circa [1863]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; sheet 29 x 22 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1
    Cataloging notes: Sheet trimmed to or within plate mark.
    Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812 Portraits.; Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00005635; 1700 - 1799 fast; Poets, American 18th century Portraits.; Poets, American. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01067794; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Commodore Barney by Wood, pinxt; Childs and Gimber sct., Circa [18--]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; sheet 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 2
    Cataloging notes: Sheet trimmed to or within plate mark.; Stauffer, D.M. American engravers upon copper and steel, 340
    Barney, Joshua, 1759-1818 Portraits.; Barney, Joshua, 1759-1818. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00235368; United States. Navy Officers Portraits.; United States. Navy. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00533204; Armed Forces Officers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00814617; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Rev. Chas. B. Boynton., Circa [186-?]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 16 x 12 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 3
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Seated pose of this Presbyterian minister and chaplain of the U.S. House of Representatives (1865-1869).
    Boynton, Charles Brandon, 1806-1883 Portraits.; Boynton, Charles Brandon, 1806-1883. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00376489; United States. Congress. House Chaplains Portraits.; United States. Congress. House. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00536930; Presbyterian Church Clergy Portraits.; Chaplains. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00852224; Presbyterian Church Clergy. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01075521; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - M.C. Meigs by Brady., Circa [between 1878 and 1881]; Series 1; 1 photoprint on cabinet card: black and white; 17 x 11 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 4
    Cataloging notes: Brady's at 625 Pennsylvania Ave., Washington, D.C., 1878-1881.; Title from handwritten notation on verso of cabinet card.
    Meigs, Montgomery C. (Montgomery Cunningham), 1816-1892 Portraits.; Meigs, Montgomery C. (Montgomery Cunningham), 1816-1892. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00170772; Military engineers United States Portraits.; Military engineers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01021162; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - William Henry Boyd, 1825-1887., Circa [1887]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: black and white; 21 x 12 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 5
    Cataloging notes: From: Boyd's Directory of the District of Columbia, 1888. Washington: Boyd, c1887.
    Boyd, Wm. H. (William H.) Portraits.; Boyd, Wm. H. (William H.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01485465; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Gen. Clingman., Circa 186-?]; Series 1; 1 photoprint on carte-de-visite mount: black and white; 10 x 6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 6
    Clingman, T. L. (Thomas Lanier), 1812-1897 Portraits.; Clingman, T. L. (Thomas Lanier), 1812-1897. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00244192; Confederate States of America. Army Officers Portraits.; Confederate States of America. Army. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00539981; Armed Forces Officers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00814617; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Rev. Father Walter, pastor, St. Patrick's., Circa [18--]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 10 x 8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 7
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Jacob Ambrose Walter was pastor of St. Patrick's Church in Washington, D.C., 1860-1894.; This was Washingtoniana Vertical File: 0252.
    Walter, J. A. (Jacob Ambrose), d. 1894 Portraits.; Catholic Church Washington (D.C.) Clergy Portraits.
  - B. Perley., Circa [between 1860 and 1880]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 9 x 6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 8
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.
    Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887 Portraits.; Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00006176; Journalists Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Journalists. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00984188; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Henry D. Cooke., Circa [between 1871 and 1881]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: black and white; 31 x 24 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 9
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photomechanical reproduction.; Cooke was the first Governor of the District of Columbia, 1871-1873.
    Cooke, Henry David, 1825-1881 Portraits.; Cooke, Henry David, 1825-1881. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00164261; Politicians Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Politicians. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01069915; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - W.W. Corcoran., Circa [ 1860]; Series 1; 1 photoprint on carte-de-visite mount: black and white; 11 x 7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 10
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of carte-de-visite.; Inscription on face of photoprint: "Mrs. Harris from W.W. Corcoran."
    Corcoran, W. W. (William Wilson), 1798-1888. http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80025930; Corcoran, W. W. (William Wilson), 1798-1888. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00051066; Bankers Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Bankers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00826798; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Dr. Hall: office on Penna. Ave. between ninth and tenth sts. N.W., Circa [between 1870 and 1880]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 23 x 17 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 11
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Dr. Hall at 909 Pennsylvania Ave., Washington, circa 1870-1880.
    Hall, James C., Dr. Portraits.; Physicians Washington (D.C.) Portraits.
  - Amos Kendall by Chs. Fenderich del.; Bannerman sc., Circa [ 1841]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic; image 23 x 13 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 12
    Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869 Portraits.; Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00163951; Postmasters United States Portraits.; Postmasters. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01073157; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Clark Mills, sculptor., Circa [18--]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 10 x 7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 13
    Mills, Clark, 1810-1883 Portraits.; Mills, Clark, 1810-1883. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00226303; Sculptors United States Portraits.; Sculptors. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01109473; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Rev. Dr. Jno. P. Newman: pastor Metropolitan M.E. Church., Circa [between 1869 and 1879]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 19 x 15 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 14
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Seated portrait of Newman, chaplain of the U.S. Senate, 1869-1874, and pastor of the Washington Metropolitan M.E. Church, 1869-1879, and 1885-1887.
    Newman, John Philip, 1826-1899 Portraits.; Newman, John Philip, 1826-1899. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00364338; United States. Congress. Senate Chaplains Portraits.; United States. Congress. Senate. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00530422; Methodist Episcopal Church Washington (D.C.) Clergy Portraits.; Methodist Episcopal Church. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00541689; Chaplains. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00852224; Clergy. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00864014; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - John Howard Payne engd by H.B. Hall and Sons., Circa [ 1850]; ??a 1850; ??irca 1850; Series 1; 1 print: planographic; image 27 x 17 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 16
    Payne, John Howard, 1791-1852 Portraits.; Payne, John Howard, 1791-1852. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00002639; Actors United States Portraits.; Actors. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00796296; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - M.B. Brady., Circa [186-?]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 20 x 13 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 17
    Brady, Mathew B., approximately 1823-1896 Portraits.; Brady, Mathew B., approximately 1823-1896. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01809348; Photographers United States Portraits.; Photographers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01061605; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Albert Pike., Circa [between 1868 and 1880]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 22 x 16 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 18
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Seated pose of this author and Freemason, resident in Washington from 1868.
    Pike, Albert, 1809-1891 Portraits.; Pike, Albert, 1809-1891. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00187823; Freemasons United States Portraits.; Freemasons. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00533636; Authors, American Portraits.; Authors, American. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00821764; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - W.W. Seaton., Circa [between 1858 and 1866]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 9 x 6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 19
    Seaton, William Winston, 1785-1866 Portraits.; Seaton, William Winston, 1785-1866. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00209284; Journalists Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Journalists. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00984188; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - William T. Smithson of Washington City, D.C. engraved by J.C. Buttre from a photograph., Circa [ 1860]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; sheet 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 20
    Cataloging notes: Sheet trimmed to or within plate mark.; Portrait of Smithson, publisher of: The Union pulpit. Washington, 1860.
    Smithson, William T. Portraits.; Smithson, William T. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00427892; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Yours truly Emma D.E.N. Southworth by Whitechurch., Circa [between 1860 and 1880]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; sheet 19 x 11 cm (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 21
    Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte, 1819-1899 Portraits.; Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte, 1819-1899. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00061978; 1800 - 1899 fast; Novelists, American 19th century Portraits.; Novelists, American. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01039688; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Byron Sunderland., Circa [18--]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 11 x 8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 22
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Portrait of this Presbyterian minister and chaplain of the U.S. Senate (1861-1864 and 1873-1879).
    Sunderland, B. (Byron), 1819-1901 Portraits.; Sunderland, B. (Byron), 1819-1901. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00235207; United States. Congress. Senate Chaplains Portraits.; United States. Congress. Senate. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00530422; Presbyterian Church Clergy Portraits.; Chaplains. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00852224; Presbyterian Church Clergy. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01075521; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Mrs. Marcia Van Ness engraved by T.B. Welch from a painting by F. Alexander., Circa 18--]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; sheet 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 23
    Van Ness, Marcia Burns, 1782-1832 Portraits.; Philanthropists Washington (D.C.) Portraits.
  - Washington: equesn. statue of Genl. Washington lith by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [between 1861 and 1871]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 18 x 11 cm. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 24
    Cataloging notes: Equestrian statue of George Washington by Clark Mills, now at Washington Circle, Washington, D.C.
    Washington, George, 1732-1799 Monuments Washington (D.C.) Pictorial works.; Washington, George, 1732-1799. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00178100; Monuments. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01025892; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - William Wirt drawn from life and engraved by J.B. Longacre., Circa [1832]; Series 1; 1 print: intaglio; plate mark 17 x 11 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 25
    Wirt, William, 1772-1834 Portraits.; Wirt, William, 1772-1834. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00156358; Attorneys general United States Portraits.; Attorneys general. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00820898; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - [Group of Washington businessmen]., 1864 April 26; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 20 x 26 cm. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 26
    Cataloging notes: Group portrait of six Washington businessmen, dated April 26, 1864, and listed as: Thomas E. Lloyd, Peter M. Du Bant, John Earp, John H. Bird, Robert H. Graham, and John B. Turton.
    Businessmen Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Businessmen. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00842951; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - [Group of Washington teachers]., Circa 1879; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 17 x 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 27
    Cataloging notes: Handwritten notation at bottom: Handy and Chester, 1879.; A group of 23 women and men, apparently teachers. Includes Benjamin F. Lloyd, a school trustee.
    Lloyd, Benjamin F. Portraits.; Teachers Washington (D.C.) Portraits.
  - H. Greenough., Circa 19--?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic; image 16 x 12 cm. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 28
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten notation on verso of printing.
    Greenough, Horatio, 1805-1852 Portraits.; Greenough, Horatio, 1805-1852. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00010665; Sculptors United States Portraits.; Sculptors. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01109473; United States. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204155; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Sailors from the USS Illinois, McKinley funeral by Clinedinst Studio, 207 F St., Wash'n, D.C., Circa [1901]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 17 x 22 cm. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 29
    McKinley, William, 1843-1901 Death and burial Pictorial works.; Funeral rites and ceremonies Washington (D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Hearse at corner of treasury, Pa. Ave. and 15th St., McKinley funeral by Clinedinst Studio, 207 F St., Wash'n, D.C., Circa [1901]; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 30
  - Flowers sent by foreign legations, McKinley funeral Clinedinst Studio, 207 F St., Wash'n, D.C., Circa [1901]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 31
  - Portrait of Peter Force., Circa [ 1967]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 32
    Cataloging notes: Title from typewritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Photoprint of portrait, 1857, by John Mix Stanley, of Force, in the Rare Book Division of the Library of Congress.
    Force, Peter, 1790-1868 Portraits.; Force, Peter, 1790-1868. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00188995; Historians Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Printers Washington (D.C.) Portraits.; Historians. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00957686; Printers. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01076585; Washington (D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01204505; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - Tombstone of Peter Force by Reni News Photos, Incorporated., Circa [ 1967]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 23 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 33
    Cataloging notes: Title from typewritten notation on verso of photoprint.; Monument in the Rock Creek Cemetery, Washington, D.C.
    Force, Peter, 1790-1868 Tomb Pictorial works.; Force, Peter, 1790-1868. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00188995; Rock Creek Cemetery (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; Rock Creek Cemetery (Washington, D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00722733; Tombs. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01152439; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - Inscription and carving on the monument to Peter Force in Rock Creek Cemetery by Reni News Photos, Incorporated., Circa [ 1967]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 23 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 34
    Cataloging notes: Title from typewritten notation on verso of photoprint.; The books carved into the alcove depict volumes printed by Force, to make available significant papers about the history of the United States.
  - Part of a centennial exhibit opened in the fall of 1967 in the foyer of the Rare Book Division, Library of Congress by Reni News Photos, Incorporated., Circa [ 1967]; Series 1; 1 photoprint: black and white; 23 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 35
    Cataloging notes: Title from typewritten notation on verso of photoprint.; The exhibit shows selected books and pamphlets from the Peter Force Library, on exhibit, Oct. 2, 1967-March 29, 1968.
    Force, Peter, 1790-1868 Library Exhibitions Pictorial works.; Library of Congress. Rare Book Division Exhibitions Pictorial works.
  - Washington: Military Asylum lith. by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [185-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 36
    Cataloging notes: "19."; The Military Asylum, which was established in 1851, and whose name was changed in 1859 to Soldiers' Home and in 1972 to United States Soldiers' and Airmen's Home. Shows three people on the grounds.
    United States Soldiers' Home Pictorial works.; United States Soldiers' Home. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00516835; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - Washington: Military Asylum lith. by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [185-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 37
    Cataloging notes: The Military Asylum, which was established in 1851, and whose name was changed in 1859 to Soldiers' Home and in 1972 to United States Soldiers' and Airmen's Home. Shows six people on the grounds.
  - Military Asylum, Washington lith. by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [185-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 38
    Cataloging notes: The Military Asylum, which was established in 1851, and whose name was changed in 1859 to Soldiers' Home and in 1972 to United States Soldiers' and Airmen's Home. Shows three people on the grounds.
  - Pension Building, Washington, D.C.., Circa [1900]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: color; 10 x 14 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 39
    Cataloging notes: "120."; Postcard.
    Pension Building (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; Pension Building (Washington, D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00669375; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - U.S. Arsenal., Circa 18--?]; Series 1; 1 print; image 7 x 10 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 40
    U.S. Arsenal (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Washington: U.S. Arsenal lith. by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [186-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 41
  - U.S. Arsenal, Washington., Circa 186-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 19 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 42
  - The Washington Arsenal., Circa 1861]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: black and white; 20 x 25 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 43
    Cataloging notes: Handwritten notation on verso reads: "From Harper's Weekly, 1861."; U.S. Arsenal in Washington, D.C.; now Fort Lesley J. McNair.
  - District of Columbia: U.S. Arsenal, Washington., Circa 186-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 44
  - Washington: U.S. Genl. Post Office., Circa 185-?]; Series 1; 1 print: color; image 7 x 10 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 45
    Cataloging notes: U.S. General Post Office, built between 1839 and 1844, located between 7th and 8th and E and F Streets, N.W.
    U.S. General Post Office (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Washington: U.S. Genl. Post Office lith. by E. Sachse and Company., Circa [185-?]; Series 1; 1 print: planographic, color; image 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)